Uh so my name is Amir Schvad. I'm sorry
you have to see two visuals of me. Um
I'm a I'm a venture part I'm a general
partner in a fund. So I'm uh I joined
the dark side about uh three years ago.
I invest in startups uh specifically
around dev tools and AI. Uh Tesla is one
of my uh investments. Um super happy to
be here. Thank you for having me. Um I
started my career as an engineer at um
at Microsoft. I worked on uh SharePoint
andnet. Uh then moved to Google. Uh
joined developer relations and worked on
uh Chrome and cloud and Android. Um then
joined Slack. Somebody said that Slack
sucks or like has some export uh export
problems. I'm sorry. Uh I joined Slack
two weeks before we launched the
platform and left when we had 250,000
weekly active developers. Um and if you
don't know the reason the difference
between correlation and causation, you
would say I choose companies based on
the colors of their logo. And that
breaks now. Uh I joined Twitch as the VP
of the API for Twitch. Uh connecting
between uh Twitch and game developers
like Ubisoft and uh Riot and EA, which
was a lot of fun. And uh then I created
my own startup called Reshuffle which
got acquired by Twitter. So uh Jack
Dorsey got me to open up the API and
then Elon closed it and fired our asses
again. Um I hope that will not be
broadcasted.
Uh and because this is pretty easy uh I
also wrote two books. One of them is on
designing bots. So about eight years ago
I said we're going to converse with
software. I did not predict LLMs. I
would probably be a lot richer if I
would predict LLMs, but I did say uh
conversational interfaces are going to
be the future. Uh and I got a nice
O'Reilly animal, which is like really
awesome, right? Usually people get fish
these days. Uh but I convinced him
O'Reilly that Siberian husky is the most
verbose animal in the animal kingdom.
And I sent him a video of a Siberian
husky say, "I love you. I love you." and
he he was convinced to give me disabing
husky. True story. And then another
another uh book about uh building APIs.
Okay. Um we're going to talk about bots.
Uh I I How many of you are actual
engineers?
Awesome. Okay. I wasn't sure. I kept it
a little bit high level, but we can talk
and we can deep dive uh and we can share
experiences. So have a a conversation
here. Um,
so why why do we code with AI? First of
all, move faster product, uh, be more
productive. Um, I think that now if
you're an engineer and you're not using
AI, you're left behind. Uh, and that's
the that's the truth. Um I also think
that avoiding a lot of mundane tasks
especially with the shift left as
engineers we're expected to be also the
SRRES also to be the QA also to be maybe
the security and I think you'll be
somebody will be talking about that so
like a lot of the things that are
expected of us not just coding uh is
also could be done with AI uh moving
forward but the key is the last one
which is do not be left behind. And if
you're using AI, you're probably in the
right place. Um, now we had a
conversation initially about what is it?
What is AI and what sorry, what is bots
and what's are what are agents? And I
want to give you my uh way of thinking
about this. So there's the co-pilots.
That's the ones that's the ones that
most of you are using right now. Okay,
this is claude or uh claude code uh or
cursor
uh or that's something that you are the
pilot. Okay, you are in charge. Uh and
it helps you. It's your co-pilot. Then
you have autonomous agents. I don't
think any of you are using autonomous
agents right now. Very few. I think
we're like maybe a year before we're
going to have in any organiza in every
organization an autonomous agent that
does a task. Basically Ryan Hoover from
Product Hunt coined the word synthetic
humans. So he envisioned a world where
we as engineers are going to work
together with these synthetic humans in
an environment like Slack, like Jira in
order to achieve a task. And we're
moving towards that autonomous. And I'm
going to show you a few examples of
that. And then the last thing which I
really really hate the name of is vibe
coding. I think vibe coding is a
horrible terrible name. It's it's more
uh because it it it's more of a PM
coding, right? There's a subject matter
expert who has intent and they want to
code and the AI converse with them as as
an engineer or or somebody that you like
abuse sometimes because of conversation
that you have with vi coding. But I
think vibe coding is is not co-pilot
because it does not assume that you are
in charge. You're not the engineer. Uh
but it's also not an autonomous agent
because you are in charge of the
business uh aspects of of building it.
Does that make sense? Okay.
So let's give examples. Uh I wanted to
put this as a but you all know about
cursor. You all said you're using
cursor. I'm not going to talk about
cursor. If your company is not using
cursor or they don't want to use
something they wanted to use something
that has a lot more security in mind and
on your own cloud you could use tab 9.
Not a lot of companies uh know about tab
9 but tab 9 is a is a great uh
replacement to cursor if you want to if
you want to train your own AI and have
all the data stays in your stay in your
own uh cloud. So if you have uh HIPPA or
FINRA concerns and you want to uh train
your own AI and your own code, then Tab
9 is a great uh great example of that.
Okay, so we talked these are the
co-pilots. You all you all know about
them. I'm going to keep it short and not
talk about them. Okay,
now let's talk about a few agents. The
first one which you probably also the
videos on uh on the interweb is about
Devon. How many of you used Devon in the
past? It kind of sucked right in the
beginning. Uh and everybody thought that
company's going to go broke. It actually
I I met the team. They're actually north
of a hund00 million of revenue. So Devon
is actually in production. Devon Devon
is like a member of your team uh that
you could use and you can actually talk
to in Slack and say, "Hey, take care of
this or take care of this bug or do this
change in production." Um why am I
telling you that? I'm telling you that
because like I think most of the bots
will initially suck and that's okay. If
you're old enough to remember the old
phones, the mobile phones, they kind of
suck. they were heavy and the battery
life was was Uh but they improved.
So set like if you if you have a bot
that you're using like Devon, it doesn't
provide you with what you want,
continuously
test it and evaluate it. I think that's
one of the best practices like don't
just get stuck on version 0.1 and say it
doesn't work for me. Continuously
evaluate uh these bots. Does that make
sense? Okay,
so uh Devon acts like a sui uh software
engineering uh agent that you can
actually talk to in all your interfaces,
assign bugs to uh and it and it
continuously works as an agent in your
team and I think we're going to see a
lot more of these uh in in the future. I
think we're like a year from having
productive agents that are helping us uh
on an ongoing basis.
Another one that I kind of like because
I really as an engineer I really really
hated testing is heel.dev.
Basically heel.dev takes a blackbox
approach to your website and start
crawling it and doing blackbox testing
to your site. Uh I really like it
because I don't want to tell my bot what
to test and what not to test. I want to
give it a URL and I want it to figure
out what is a good experience, what is
not, what is a mobile experience, what
is not, what looks well and what doesn't
and to open all the bugs either for me
or for Devon. Right? So now you can have
multiple bots communicating with each
other and that's awesome. That's where
like I think the value actually uh
compounds. So, heel.dev is a great thing
to to test and it helps you um do uh
blackbox testing on on websites and I
think they're going to move to uh APIs
in backend as well.
Um another interesting one which uh
engineers really hate, maybe you're
different is talking to uh marketing and
salespeople. How many of you really like
that?
Okay, awesome. We have one.
uh from my perspective like there's
there's a slack channel and these sales
people keep on asking question does the
customers asking do do we support this
when is this feature happening um so do
D do is a great uh startup coming from
uh Silicon Valley uh I know the founder
is he's amazing and what it does it
creates the docs for your application
and also supports that application on an
ongoing basis internally
So if you have if your uh customer
success has questions they ask in the
channel and do answers them which is
pretty awesome because if you think
about like the things that suck the most
is meetings and questions from
salespeople right and this helps you
with that with that problem. Um I I've
played with it and it answers a lot of
questions that that are mundane and that
are repeated. It also looks at human
answers and then remembers them and
repeats them when when needed, which I
which I think is very very neat.
So check out DOSU.
Um last thing I'm going to say is I
think there's also a niche for a lot of
like very um subject matter expert bots.
So this is an example of code
optimization.
uh in some cases you need to optimize
specific code and I think general AI
will not be very good there because of
optimization is a skill that only very
few uh engineers really have. So uh code
flesh is built by a team from Facebook
whose sole job was to optimize code. So
basically they built uh a a bunch of
best practices and trained their AI to
optimize code. Right now it only works
on Python I think but uh they're moving
into doing that for multiple code bases
and multiple uh open source projects. So
basically training the AI to optimize
code. It also does the testability. So
it builds a test for a certain function
and then optimizes the code, sees that
it passes all the tests and then submits
the PR, which I think is really really
awesome. And if you have these uh
specific bots that continuously look at
different aspects of your code, whether
it's secure, whether it's uh optimized,
where maybe it's costefficient. We're
going to see multiple bots like this
that uh are going to help us build
better software.
Okay,
last thing, vibe coding. Uh how many of
you vibed code? I'm sorry for using
that. Uh yeah, it's it's pretty awesome
for prototyping,
but the minute you actually want it to
be like production ready, I feel we're
not there 100%. I had an interesting
conversation with the founder of lovable
and I told him that like I think there's
a lot of opportunity you know lovable
it's uh uh I told him there's a lot of
opportunity to build uh apps for
enterprise using lovable and he said yes
but there's a problem with
predictability of outcome and guard
rails and basically it's like a nice way
of saying we don't want the AI to delete
all the data from our customers and ruin
our business uh which I think we're
still we're still in the in this era. So
if I were to use vibe coding in an
enterprise, I would only use it as a
read only right now and have write
access when I think there's more
predictability of outcome. Uh but also
like for rapid prototyping, I love vibe
coding for rapid prototyping.
Interesting startups that I'm seeing in
this area are around mobile uh
prototyping. So starting to move from
web into native code in iOS and Android
and I think there's a lot of opportunity
to to do smart things there. Does that
make cool? Okay. So now how am I on
time? I'm good on time. Let's talk about
where AI is currently great. And as you
can see I made it currently because I
think this presentation would probably
be obsolete in like two three months. So
where where AI is currently great uh in
a well- definfined scope. So if you have
a spec that's great. I'm a true believer
that in the future will be not prompt
driven by spec driven for sure. There's
no there's no future where serious
product will be built using prompts. It
will probably be based on specs and
cascading specs probably. Um it's better
in in web uh and front end rather than
back end. Do you know why
any
>> sorry
>> it's trained on the internet?
>> Exactly. It's trained on the internet
and most of the internet is front end.
Uh it's and and for that reason it's
also uh on most common languages than
rare languages. So if you're building
for JavaScript that's probably better
than building for C++. Uh and also for a
popular framework. I had a startup that
I was working with and they were using
Astro and once we moved to Nex.js
AI like felt so comfortable now and it
gave us such a good experience because
it was still it was hallucinating a lot
more with Astro.
Okay, where does it currently suck? And
it doesn't mean that you don't need to
use it. It needs it means that you're
you as a human need to work around
problems there. One of them is with
complex tasks. Have you ever tried to
get AI to write code around OOTH?
I don't think most humans know how to
work around oath for sure. Uh when I was
at Slack, uh the number one complaint we
had with our API was that the OOTH flow
was too complex to authenticate with the
Slack API. But AI really really doesn't
work well with OOTH or complex things
like billing. Uh the the the current
best practice that I can think about and
I've worked with uh base uh a little bit
with base 44 which is another vibe
coding is to create Lego blocks for
things that you know the AI will have
hard time with and then let it wire into
that. So say hey I have this piece of
code that already implements the OOTH
that I need. just connect into the
interface, connect the front end into
that interface. Uh so the AI is much
better working with working Lego blocks
rather than um implementing them. Um
understand multiple systems and APIs. So
MCP is starting to help there. But still
AI has a problem understanding which
system to choose and from these systems
which API to choose and which version to
choose and which parameters to give each
of those APIs and you'll need to be um
more descriptive or use MCP to solve
that problem.
Uh large context multiple repos. Have
you ever tried to give it uh enterprise
level repos? It's the best way to get a
shrug out of an API, out of AI, like
what should I do? I don't know which
repo to use. Uh, and the largest the the
larger the context is, the more uh
hallucinations you get. Uh, abstract or
vague instructions. And I don't know if
you've ever went into a rage circle with
your AI where you tell it, fix it, and
it doesn't. And I I fixed it and then it
doesn't fix it. Uh, I have screenshots
of friends that have abusive
relationship with their AI around fixing
bugs. You're such a horrible AI. I know.
I'm sorry. And stuff like that. Um, but
a lot of the times you'll need to do the
debugging of the hard stuff. Uh, and
actually base 44 is now offering a
service to have engineers debug your
vibe coding, which I think is probably
the worst job in the world.
Uh and again I think that's why I think
that's why specs actually make sense. Um
and then I think predictability of
outcome is interesting. Um never try to
write an SDK with AI because the next
time you'll do it, it will for sure
create breaking changes. It will change
the name of the functions. It will
change the order of the inputs. It will
do something that will make your
customers very very mad. Uh we tried in
a company here in Austin called Liblab
to actually replace templates with AI
and we couldn't figure it out. The at
the end of the day it could not create
uh uh solid interface. The problem was
not the implementation, the problem was
the interface. The interface kept
breaking with every version. Um so if
you have if you really need
predictability of outcome I think you
still need to use either humans or
templates.
Okay,
so last slide uh best practice
clearly define your task. Use specs. I
think that's very important. Uh define
the scope. Uh test and find the right
bots for you. Um bots that are used that
suck continuously know and test them. Um
test and verify the outcome. When the AI
says, "Hey, I've done it." It might not
it might have like not done it. Um I I
think specs of the future and if you go
into this uh site um they're trying to
keep the good team from Tesla are trying
to keep uh everything updated around the
bots that are in this uh ecosystem and
what's new in in this uh in this
business. Okay,
I promised you a dance. I you know what?
I'll I'll do a dance. Um okay, nobody's
too cool for school. When I work when I
worked at at uh um at Google, I was one
of the people that managed uh Google IO.
Do you know what's Google IO? It's a big
event, 50,000 people. And we did a study
uh how to improve people's score on
presentations.
Uh you know what's the biggest fear in
in America?
>> Public speaking.
>> Public speaking more than death. So
people would rather give uh be dead than
give the eulogy which is kind of
freaking out. So we did a study with a
company and we said uh how can we get
people to not be fearful of speaking. So
we did this and we figured out a dance
that you have to do not in front of the
audience but behind the stage and if you
do this dance then you get uh better uh
feeling and then you perform better and
you get better scores even if you not if
you don't know what you're talking
about. Okay. So I'm going to show you
the dance and then all of you are going
to stand up and do the dance and you had
a good takeaway from this uh from this
presentation. Okay. So 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3
1 2 3 1 2 1 2 1 2 1 2 1 one one
superhero stand. Okay, so now everybody
stand up. I did this for 3,000 people,
so nobody's too cool for school. Okay,
up.
Okay. One, two, three. One, two, three.
One, two, three. One, two, three. One,
two, one, two, one, two, one, two, one,
one, one, one. Superhero stand.
[Applause]